Preliminary Inventory of the Marek Lehnert Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound recordings of interviews and events, 1984-1996; 137 audio cassettes (Box 7-10)
  - Sound recording of a performance by Roberto Begnigni and of Lech Wałęsa's first official visit to Rome as Polish president, 4 February 1991 (Box 8)
    Side A: recording of Italian singer Lucio Dalla and Italian actor Robert Begnigni, in "Attenti Al Lupo" (Peter and the Wolf), 1991.
    Side B: Wałęsa's first official visit to Rome as Polish president, 4 February 1991. Andrzej Drzycimski, Wałęsa's spokesman, talks about the importance of each meeting between Pope John Paul II and Wałęsa's. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006122
  - Sound recording of Lech Wałęsa's visit to Rimini, Italy, 26 August 1990; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006123 (Box 8)
  - Sound recording of Liliana Cavani, Vittorio Taviani, and Gian Luigi Rondi, and Eduard Shevardnadze, 19 February - 14 March 1991 (Box 8)
    Side A: Italian filmmakers Liliana Cavani, Vittorio Taviani, and Gian Luigi Rondi talk about Polish cinema, Rome, February 19, 1991. In Italian.
    Side B: Eduard Shevardnadze, Georgia's head of state, comments on the impact of Perestroika on the Soviet Union and other countries. In Russian, with Italian interpreter. Samarcanda, 14 March 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006126
  - Sound recording of Italian radio broadcast about Polish refugees in Italy, 24 February 1988 (Box 8)
    In Italian; includes translated statements by Polish refugees. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006127
  - Sound recording at "Latina," a transitional camp for refugees in Rome and interview with Polish refugees, 23 July 1987 (Box 8)
    The refugees primarly discuss the camp's living conditions. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006128
  - Sound recording of Archbishop Szczepan Wesoły, Cardinal Józef Glemp, and Tadeusz Mazowiecki, 26 October 1990 (Box 8)
    Side A: At a conference in Rome about Polish immigration: (1) Polish Cardinal Glemp talks about the role and spiritual presence of Roman Catholic Church; (2) Polish Archbishop Wesoły, pastor of immigrants, lecture about Polish immigration after WWII.
    Side B: Tadeusz Mazowiecki, first non-communist Prime Minister of Poland, calling for cooperation between Poland and Polish immigrants scattered all over the world. Senator Anna Bogucka lecture about identity of Polish immigrants with Polish culture around the world. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006130
  - Sound recording of interviews with Polish pilgrims in Santiago de Compostela, Spain, august 1989 (Box 8)
    Hiszpania. At a key destination of Christian pilgrimages, the recording includes greetings by Pope John Paul II and interviews with young Polish pilgrims. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006131
  - Sound recording of interviews with Lech Wałęsa and Bishop Tadeusz Pieronek, 27 August 1990; October 1993 (Box 8)
    Side A: Short interview of Wałęsa, 27 August 1990.
    Side B: Interview with Polish Bishop Tadeusz Pieronek, 25 October 1993. Pope John Paul II appeal to Poles, Rome, 1993. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006132
  - Sound recording of an interview with Marian Jurczyk, 9 June 1988 (Box 8)
    Jurczyk, Polish politician and Solidarity trade union activist, talks about his political activities and repressions in Poland. Jurczyk elaborates on the demoralization among youth in Poland, caused by lack of perspectives; he also comments on the necessity of implementing political and economic reforms in Poland. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006133
  - Sound recording of interviews of Józef Ŝlisz, Janusz Onyszkiewicz, and Andrzej Malanowski, December 1989 (Box 8)
    Side A: Ŝlisz, Deputy Speaker of the Senate and a longtime leader of "Solidarity of Individual Farmers," reflects on his visit to Parma.
    Side B: Lecture by Onyszkiewicz, member of the Polish Parliament, about the history of the "Solidarity" movement in Poland. Also includes an interview (in Italian) with Maria Macciocchi, Italian feminist militant and leftist dissident, and interview of Andrzej Malanowski, Polish Socialist Party (PPS), about political parties in new democratic Poland. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006249
  - Sound recording of interviews with Polish women living in Africa, made during Pope John Paul II's visit to Africa, 11 March 1992 (Box 8)
    Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006250
  - Sound recording of Bogusław Steczek and Professor Krzysztof Żaboklicki, 9 March - 8 April 1992 (Box 8)
    Side A: Steczek, Assistant General of the Jesuits for Central and Eastern Europe, liaison between John Paul II and the Church and and the Jesuits in these countries, talks about the Catholic community and Jesuit mission in Russia. Rome, 9 March 1992.
    Side B: Żaboklicki, President of International Union of the Institutes of Archaeology, History and Art History in Rome, talks about the presence of Italian culture in Central Europe and Polish culture in Italy, 8 April 1992. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006251
  - Sound recording of an interview with Archbishop Kazimierz Swiatek and a meeting of Marek Edelman with the Polish community in Rome, 12-17 December 1991 (Box 8)
    Światek, Vatican Archbishop of Minsk, Belarus, discusses his work in a mission in Belarus, 12 December 1991.
    Side B: Edelman, last surviving leader of the Warsaw Ghetto uprising of 1943, meets with the Polish community in Rome, 17 December 1991 (part I). Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006252
  - Sound recording of interviews with Krzysztof Małachowski and Marek Edelman, 17 December 1991 (Box 8)
    Side A: Interview with Father Małachowski, from Eucharistic Apostolate Foundation for Disabled Children: "Dzieci Dzieciom" (from Children to Children).
    Side B: Edelman interview in Rome (part II). Edelman talks about the Jewish nation, culture, and Israeli-Palestinian relations. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006254
  - Sound recording of Bishop Józef Michalik interview, November - December 1991 (Box 8)
    Side A: Michalik, while attending the Synod of Bishops for Europe in Rome, talks about the role of the Catholic Church in Poland. Also included is a Radio Vatican broadcast about the 1991 elections in Poland, and Pope John Paul II's visit to Poland.
    Side B: Michalik discusses the Synod of Bishops for Europe in Rome. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006255
  - Sound recording of interviews of Adam Żak and Professor Jacek Woźniakowski, 13 Jan 1992, 8-13 January 1992 (Box 8)
    Side A: Żak, Kraków, a Jesuit priest, reflects on religious consciousness, Rome, 8 January 1992.
    Side B: Woźniakowski, Polish historian and writer, talks about social teachings of the Church, 13 January 1992. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006256
  - Sound recording of Józef Mirosław Życiński, 11 December 1991 (Box 8)
    Życiński, Polish Roman Catholic bishop, philosopher, theologian, journalist, and the diocesan bishop of Tarnów, talks about the European Synod in Rome. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006257
  - Sound recording of Bishop Antoni Pacyfik Dydycz interview, 6 February 1992 (Box 8)
    Dydycz (religious name: Pacyfik), Polish diocesan bishop of Drohiczyn, OFM Cap (Order of Friars Minor Capuchin), Doctor of History, discusses evangelism in Eastern European countries. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006258
  - Sound recording of Polish priests from the missionary congregation "Werbiści," Flores Island, 11 October 1989 (Box 8)
    Polish priests from Werbiści, Divine Word, the missionary congregation SDV (from Lat. Societas Divini Verbi), talk about their mission in Indonesia and challenges they encounter there. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006259
  - Sound recording of interviews with Bishop Sławoj Leszek Głódź, 8 Feb 1992 and Father Stanisław Pomykała, 12 Dec 1992, 8 February - 12 December 1992 (Box 8)
    Side A: Polish Catholic Bishop Głódź is interviewed about his participation in the conference of bishops of different faiths in Vatican. He also reflects on his experience as the Field Bishop of the Polish Army since 1991. 8 February 1992.
    Side B: Pomykała, a Catholic Priest, talks about his mission and work in Novosibirsk and Tomsk, Russia. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006260
  - Sound recording of interviews with Cardinal Andrzej Maria Deskur and Bishop Ryszard Karpiński, 17 February - 2 March 1992 (Box 8)
    Side A: Cardinal Deskur, President of the Pontifical Council for Social Communications, reflects on the essence and power of human suffering, 17 February 1992.
    Side B: Bishop Karpiński talks about shrines, pilgrimages, and priests serving Poles who live in the former Soviet Union, 2 March 1992. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006261
  - Sound recording of interviews of Rocco Buttiglione and Cardinal Fiorenzo Angelini, 7 January - 2 February 1994 (Box 9)
    Side A: Buttiglione, Italian Christian Democrat politician, interview, 7 January 1994. In Italian.
    Side B: Italian Cardinal Angelini is interviewed about popular place of pilgrimages in Poland, Częstochowa, 2 February 1994. In Italian. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006262
  - Sound recording of a family, interview with Adam Edward Boniecki, and Italian radio broadcast with Lech Wałęa, 29 January - 3 February 1991 (Box 9)
    Side A: Family sound recording, 29 January 1991.
    Side B: Boniecki, a Catholic priest, talks about the ministry of Polish diocean bishop of Przemyśl - Ignacy Tokarczuk, 2 February 1991. Also includes an Italian radio broadcast with Lech Wałęa interview, 3 February 1991 (in Italian). Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006263
  - Sound recording of Tadeusz Mazowiecki press conference and RFE interview with Tadeusz Mazowiecki, 15-17 May 1991 (Box 9)
    Side A: Mazowiecki, Polish prime minister, press conference, Rome, 15 May 1991. Side B: Mazowiecki interview, 17 May 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006264
  - Sound recording of debate about Father Jerzy Popiełuszko and General Wojciech Jaruzelski, 19 November 1984 (Box 9)
    Debate in Rome hosted by Italian Magazine Mondoperaio (World Worker). In Italian. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006265
  - Sound recording of interviews of Professor Andrzej Stelmachowski, Wojciech Jaruzelski and Lech Wałęsa, 31 May 1988 - 13 March 1989 (Box 9)
    Side A: Stelmachowski, Polish academic and politician, is interviewed about Individual Farmers Union "Solidarity" in Poland, 21 February 1989.
    Side B: Italian radio broadcast featuring interviews with Jaruzelski, 31 May 1988, and Wałęsa, 13 March 1989. Translated from Polish into Italian. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006266
  - Sound recording of Professor Jerzy Kłoczowski conversation from 6 May 1988 and reports about strikes in Poland (Box 9)
    Side A: Conversation by telephone with a witness to demonstrations in Poland, about the wave of strikes and rallies that erupted in Polish factories and colleges in the spring of 1988, followed by arrests and other repressions; the potesters' demands included re-legalization of the "Solidarity" movement and other political reforms in Poland.
    Side B: Interview with Kłoczowski, a historian, who talks about the legacy of Kievan Ruthenia in the Polish-Lithuanian-Russian community, 6 May 1988. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006269
  - Sound recording of interviews with Włodzimierz Cimoszewicz, Archbishop Jean-Louis Pierre Tauran, and Stefan Frankiewicz, 22 June - 24 July 1996 (Box 9)
    Side A: Prime minister of Poland Cimoszewicz talks about the EU summit in Florence and hopes for Poland to be ready to join the EU by 2000, 22 June 1996.
    Side B: French Archbishop Jean-Louis Pierre Tauran, Secretary of State of Vatican, talks about the concordat between Poland and Vatican, 24 July 1996. In French. Also includes Radio Vatican broadcast interview with Stefan Frankiewicz, Polish Ambassador to Vatican, 24 July 1996. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006270
  - 50 years of Radio Vatican sound recording, 24 November 1988 (Box 9)
    Celebratory program with guests and speakers: Bishop Zenon Grocholewski and directors of Polish section, as well as several priests: Florian Pełka, Franciszek Mączyński, Stefan Filipowicz, and Ludwik Grzebień. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006273
  - Sound recording of interviews of Florian Pełka and Tomáŝ Ŝpidlik, 21 December 1994 - 23 March 1995 (Box 9)
    Side A: Father Pełka is interviewed about Congregation of Jesuits, 21 December 1994.
    Side B: Ŝpidlik, a Czech catholic priest, talks about his recollections in the Vatican, 25 March 1995. In Italian. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006274
  - Sound recording of RFE broadcasts "In the intention of the homeland and those who suffer" and "Precious death", undated (Box 9)
    Side A: "In the intention of the homeland and those who suffer" broadcast about Father Jerzy Popiełuszko.
    Side B: "Precious death" with homily by Father Franciszek Blachnicki. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006275
  - Sound recording of radio broadcast "Testament of Father Jerzy Popiełuszko" radio broadcast, undated (Box 9)
    Side A: International Center of Evangelization "Light-Life" broadcast titled "Testament of Father Jerzy Popiełuszko" from recording studio in Carlsberg. It includes a recording of Popiełuszko's last sermon before he was kidnapped and murdered by the Polish Security Service in October 1984.
    Side B: Father Franciszek Blachnicki, "In the Face of Crime: Testament of Father Jerzy Popiełuszko." Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006276
  - Radio Vatican sound recording "Ksiądz Jerzy Popiełuszko o swej pracy", undated (Box 9)
    This is about the work of Popiełuszko. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006280
  - Sound recording of Cardinal Józef Glemp interview, 7 July 1995 (Box 9)
    Side A: Glemp interview, 7 July 1995.
    Side B: News broadcast in Italian. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006281
  - Sound recording of Tadeusz Michałek interview, 10 August 1991 (Box 9)
    Side A: Michałek, a priest, talks about his missionary journeys to the United States and Malta, emphasizing the importance of contact and dialogue with the followers of different faiths. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006282
  - Sound recording of Cardinal Józef Glemp interview, 16 December 1991; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006285 (Box 9)
  - Sound recording of Konrad Hejmo, Janusz Pasierb, and Jacek Moskwa, 14 July - 30 October 1991 (Box 9)
    Side A: Hejmo, a Dominican priest, is interviewed on 15 July 1991.
    Side B: Pasierb, a priest, poet and historian, talks about the role of church in the Polish culture, and journalist and writer Jacek Moskwa talks about priest Jan Zieja, 30 October 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006286
  - Sound recording of radio broadcast about General Wojciech Jaruzelski and report on Solidarity trade union demands from Gdańsk, 31 June 1988 (Box 9)
    Side A: Radio broadcast about Jaruzelski, 31 June 1988. In Italian.
    Side B: Report concerning a list of demands published by the Solidarity trade union strike committee, and an interview with Adam Michnik. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006287
  - Sound recording of interview of Halina Mikołajska, a Polish actress, 5 August 1986; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006288 (Box 9)
  - Sound recording of Pope John Paul II's pilgrimage to Poland, February or June 1991 (Box 9)
    Side A: Pope John Paul II during pilgrimage to Poland, recorded at a church and a theater, 9 June 1991; impressions and comments by actors, writers, politicians: Andrzej Szczypiorski, Paweł Hertz, Wiktor Woroszylski, Maja Komorowska, Andrzej Stelmachowski, Father Janusz Pasierb, Ernest Bryll, Stefan Bratkowski, and others.
    Side B: John Paul II visits a Jewish Theater during his pilgrimage, June 9 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006290
  - Sound recording of Cardinal Andrzej Maria Deskur and Stefan Wilkanowicz, May 1992 (Box 9)
    Side A: Cardinal Deskur expresses his wishes on the 40th anniversary of Polish Section of RFE. Vatican Radio news broadcast.
    Side B: Wilkanowicz, a journalist, discusses a meeting of the Council for the Laity in Rome. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006291
  - Sound recording of a conversation with Latvian Cardinal Julijans Vaivods, 1987; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006295 (Box 9)
  - Sound recording of refugees interview with Władysław Siła-Nowicki, 1989 (Box 9)
    Side A: Interview with Polish refugees in Rome, 1989.
    Side B: Interview of Solidarity adviser and longtime anti-communist lawyer Władysław Siła-Nowicki, 18 February 1989. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006297
  - Sound recording of interview of Tadeusz Mazowiecki and Polish bishops about the 1994 Synod in Rome, 13 September 1994 (Box 9)
    Mazowiecki arrived in Rome as a Special Emissary of United Nations Organization to Bosnia and Herzegovina. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006298
  - Sound recording of Archbishop Tadeusz Kondrusiewicz, Bishop Stanisław Nagy, and Krzysztof Skubiszewski, 6 December 1992 - 3 July 1993 (Box 9)
    Side A: Interviews with Belarusian archbishop Kondrusiewicz and Bishop Nagy, 6 December 1992.
    Side B: Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs Skubiszewski interview, 3 July 1993. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006299
  - Sound recording of Cardinal Józef Glemp and Krzysztof Skubiszewski, 4-7 July 1990 (Box 9)
    Side A: Cardinal Glemp, 4 July 1990.
    Side B: Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs Skubiszewski press conference, Rome, 7 July 1990. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006300
  - Sound recording of interviews with Professor Bronisław Geremek and Andrzej Niemierko, 8 August 1989 - 9 June 1990 (Box 9)
    Side A: Interview with Geremek, a Polish historian and politician, Rome, 9 August 1989.
    Side B: Interview with Niemierko, an engineer and intern of IRI (The Istituto per la Ricostruzione Industriale/Industrial Reconstruction Institute), Rome, 9 June 1990. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006301
  - Sound recording of Krzysztof Skubiszewski and Leszek Balcerowicz, 7 July - 19 October 1990 (Box 9)
    Side A: Skubiszewski, Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs, Rome, 7 July 1990.
    Side B: Polish Finance Minister Balcerowicz press conference, Rome, 19 October 1990. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006302
  - Sound recording of interview with Krzysztof Skubiszewski, 22 September 1991 (Box 9)
    This interview of the Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs was conducted in Rome. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006304
  - Václav Havel sound recording, June 1990 (Box 9)
    President of the Czech Republic Havel, Dahrendorf, C. M. Martini. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006305
  - Sound recording of interview with Marini, 14 January 1987 (Box 9)
    Marini, Pizzinato, Benvenuto, is interviewed after his meeting with General Wojciech Jaruzelski. In Italian. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006307
  - Sound recording of "Country-Emigration" conference, 30 October 1990 (Box 9)
    Side A: The conference recording includes an interview with a Polish priest from Uzbekistan, Józef Świdnicki, and one of the organizers of the conference, Orłowski.
    Side B: Andrzej Stelmachowski, Marshal of the Senate, addresses the conference and Polish diaspora. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006308
  - Sound recording of Salvatore Esposito and Father Janusz Pasierb, 5 August 1990 (Box 9)
    Side A: Salvatore Esposito, student of writer Jerzy Pomianowski.
    Side B: Father Janusz Pasierb in Rome, 5 August 1990. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006368
  - Sound recording of Andrzej Szostek and Bishop Bronisław Dembowski, 1993 (Box 9)
    Side A: Polish priest and professor Andrzej Szostek, MIC, talks about about the Veritatis Splendor ("The Splendor of Truth"), an encyclical by Pope John Paul II, Rome, 5 October 1993.
    Side B: Bishop Dembowski talks about elections, Rome, 1993. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006369
  - Sound recording of Konrad Hejmo and Ambassador Henryk Kupiszewski, 11-12 January 1991 (Box 9)
    Side A: Dominican priest Konrad Hejmo talks about the pilgrimage movement, 11 January 1991.
    Side B: Ambassador Kupiszewski is interviewed after meeting with Pope John Paul II, 12 January 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006370
  - Sound recording of Szczepan Praśkiewicz, Professor Maria Poprzęcka and Professor Jan Ostrowski, 6-14 November 1991 (Box 9)
    Side A: Carmelite theologian Father Praśkiewicz talks about Saint Rafał Kalinowski, the Carmelite beatified by Pope John Paul II, 6 November 1991.
    Side B: Professor Poprzęcka, Polish art historian and director of the Institute of Art History at Warsaw University, and Professor Ostrowski, Polish art historian at the Jagiellonian University Art History Institute and director of the Royal Castle, 14 November 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006371
  - Bishop Józef Mirosław Życiński sound recording, August 1993; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006372 (Box 10)
  - Sound recording of Litwa-Łotwa (Lithuania-Latvia) from Aglona, Latvia, 1993; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006373 (Box 10)
  - Sound recording of Cardinal Myrosław I. Lubaczywski and Bishop Ivan Martyniak, 10-11 December 1991 (Box 10)
    side A. Ukrainian Cardinal Lubaczywski, Rome, 10 December 1991.
    Side B. Martyniak, bishop for Polish Ukrainian Catholics in Przemyśl from Rome, 11 December 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006374
  - Sound recording of Cardinal Józef Glemp and Cardinal Edmund Szoka, June 1994 (Box 10)
    Side A: Glemp, Polish cardinal of the Roman Catholic Church, talks about the Consistory (General Assembly of the cardinals) in the Vatican, 13-14 June 1994.
    Side B: Szoka discusses Vatican finances, 30 June 1991. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_00062375
  - Sound recording of Mario Segni, Cardinal Agostino Casaroli, and Cardinal Józef Glemp, 13 December - 20 January 1994 (Box 10)
    Side A: Italian politician Mario Segni and Cardinal Agostino Casaroli, 13 December 1993 and 20 December 1993.
    Side B: Cardinal Glemp, 20 Jan 1994. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006376
  - Angola sound recordings, June 1992; Four audio cassettes; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006377 (Box 10)
  - Sound recordings from Pope John Paul II's trip to Africa, 1-8 September 1990; Six audio cassettes; Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006381 (Box 10)
    Tape 1: Press conference with Pope John Paul II on board an aircraft during the flight to Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Also includes ceremony at the airport, 1 September 1990.
    Tape 2: Singing before the mass in Dar es Salaam, Polish missionaries, a conversation with a priest about AIDS, and singing in St. Peter's church.
    Tape 3: Poles in Songea and Mwanza, 3 September 1990, a Franciscan in Moshi, and the Burundi national anthem, 5 September 1990.
    Tape 4: Polish Carmelite missionaries in Burundi, and Pope John Paul II addresses Poles in Bujumbura, 6 September 1990.
    Tape 5: Welcoming ceremony in Rwanda, 7 September 1990, Archbishop Henryk Hoser talks about AIDS, Kigali, 7 September 1990.
    Tape 6: Tam-tams, Carmelite missionaries in Kigali, Rwanda, 8 September 1990.
  - Sound recording of Father Lewandowski and Roman Rota, July 1992 (Box 10)
    Side A: Lewandowski talks about the catechism, July 1992.
    Side B: Rota Rzymska (Roman Rota, the highest appellate tribunal of the Roman Catholic Church). Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006385
  - Sound recording of Poles in Mauritius, 15-16 October 1989 (Box 10)
    Side A: Poles in Mauritius, 15 October 1989.
    Side B: Flight from Mauritius to Rome, 16 October 1989. Use copy reference number: 2002c12_a_0006386